offshorexperts.com 2005-03-07

# Outsourcing Directory for Outsourcing Services, Outsourcing Companies, Outsourcing News and Leads

In general, OffshoreXperts.com does not collect, store, use or disclose personally identifying information except in very specific instances, such as, for example, when you enroll as an advertiser in the Services, as defined below. Whenever we collect such information, you will have a choice regarding whether to provide it, how it will be used, and to whom it will be disclosed. The instances in which OffshoreXperts.com does collect and use information are specifically described in this Privacy Policy. 

**What does this Privacy Policy cover?**  
This Privacy Policy applies to collection, use, storage and disclosure of information by OffshoreXperts.com. If there are any exceptions, we will clearly disclose them prior to collecting any information, and will give you an opportunity to choose not to participate or provide the information. By using the Services and our Web site, you consent to the collection and use of your information as we outline in this Privacy Policy. 

OffshoreXperts.com may decide to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will include the new language changes here. Please be aware that, as part of the Services, OffshoreXperts.com provides links to Web sites operated by third parties, and also provides search results and similar services to third parties for display on their own Web sites or applications. OffshoreXperts.com is not responsible for the information collection or privacy practices or the content of those third party Web sites or applications. 

**What information does OffshoreXperts.com collect and how is it used? Does OffshoreXperts.com disclose information to third parties?**  
OffshoreXperts.com may collect any or all of the following four types of information: (a) traffic or clickstream data, (b) cookies, (c) pixel tags or (d) contact information and other personally identifying information. OffshoreXperts.com's collection and use of each type of data is described below, as well as the ways (if any) in which the data may be shared with third parties. Please note that OffshoreXperts.com may transfer any information in its possession in connection with a sale of assets of the company, a sale of the company or a merger.  

**(a) Traffic or Clickstream Data.** Data about traffic and usage is not personally identifying or identifiable, and is not supplemented or combined with personally identifying or identifiable information. OffshoreXperts.com may share information it collects with certain selected third parties, but only in aggregated, anonymous form. For example, we may tell an advertiser that a certain number of people visited a certain area on our Web site, or searched Web sites for the term "offshore outsourcing." OffshoreXperts.com collects some information regarding use of the Services by observing browser functions and the files (pages) users access. For example, OffshoreXperts.com's servers collect information about the site from which you entered to enable OffshoreXperts.com to calculate and pay its affiliates, information about the most frequently searched terms to help its advertisers provide the most relevant search results, information about usage to check for fraudulent behavior or other abnormalities and to ensure that our Services are technically superior. In addition to the foregoing applications, OffshoreXperts.com uses the information (in aggregate form) to better design the Services. 

**(b) Cookies.** Like many sites, OffshoreXperts.com collects information about online behavior using cookies. These cookies contain identification information that enables us to see how our users are interacting with our site and how frequently they are returning, as well as to streamline their experiences using the Services. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifiable information. Cookies let us know about repeat visitors and if we are delivering quality products and services. 

OffshoreXperts.com may also use cookies to identify which sites our repeat visitors are coming from, so that we can place more of our online advertising on these sites, and can, where necessary, pay our affiliates and other business partners. To OffshoreXperts.com, using information within cookies is an anonymous way to survey how we are doing and to look for ways to improve our Services. 

You may set your browser software to reject cookies, but you may not be able to use all of the features of the Services. OffshoreXperts.com may share information about usage of the Services with third parties, but only in aggregated, anonymous form. In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser. 

**(c) Pixel Tags.** OffshoreXperts.com shares web site usage information about visitors to our web site with reputable third-party advertising companies for the purpose of targeting and measuring the effectiveness of our Internet advertisements on this site and other sites. For this purpose, OffshoreXperts.com and our third-party advertising companies note some of the pages you visit on our Web site through the use of pixel tags (also called clear gifs and web beacons). 

**(d) Contact Information or Personally Identifying Information.** OffshoreXperts.com can obtain access to your name, e-mail address and other contact information only (1) when you become a provider or buyer with OffshoreXperts.com, provide comments, submit a problem, or request information from OffshoreXperts.com and provide your name or return contact information, or (2) in connection with special offers or contests (such as promotions and giveaways). 

OffshoreXperts.com may share information with companies who work on our behalf to provide certain services, such as email processing and delivery and conducting research and analysis. These companies are prohibited from using this information for any other purpose or from sharing this information with other companies. 

OffshoreXperts.com may also provide information in response to valid legal process, such as subpoenas, search warrants and court orders, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. 

Contact information provided in connection with problems, comments or requests is used only to respond to those problems, comments or requests. This information is not stored or used in connection with traffic or clickstream data and is provided to a third party only as necessary to respond to the comment, problem or request. Finally, you may choose to provide contact information, other personally identifying information, and demographic information in order to participate in optional surveys or contests, which are run for promotional purposes. OffshoreXperts.com uses such information to send you information about its products and to notify you if you win the contest. Users may opt-out of receiving such communications at any time by contacting OffshoreXperts.com. 

**Is data stored by OffshoreXperts.com secure?**  
Any and all postings and/or transmissions done on OffshoreXperts.com systems can and are routinely monitored by staff for legal and terms of service violations. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, OffshoreXperts.com has put in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information it collects online. However, data security is a constantly evolving art and science. You should consider any communication that you transmit to OffshoreXperts.com (such as data, questions or answers, comments, or suggestions) as non-confidential, and agree that OffshoreXperts.com will not be liable or responsible if information that belongs to you is intercepted and used by an unintended recipient. 

**Does OffshoreXperts.com collect personally identifying information from or about children?**  
OffshoreXperts.com uses reasonable efforts not to collect, use or disclose individually identifiable information from children under the age of 13. The Services are not targeted at children, and children may not register for any portions of the Services that require registration. 

**How can I access or correct any personally identifying information about me?**  
To request a copy of the personally identifiable information you have sent to OffshoreXperts.com, please send an e-mail containing your request to [**privacy@OffshoreXperts.com**](mailto:privacy@OffshoreXperts.com). You must provide your full name and the e-mail from which the request is received (and to which the response will be sent) must match the e-mail on file with OffshoreXperts.com. You may then correct or delete such information using the procedures specified in the e-mail. 

**How do I find out more about OffshoreXperts.com's information practices?**  
If you have any questions about anything in this Privacy Policy, or about collection of personally identifiable information, or information generally, please contact OffshoreXperts.com as follows:  

You may also use the above contact information if you think any information about you is inaccurate, incomplete, or if you want to change the sort of information about you that OffshoreXperts.com may have collected. 

This Privacy Policy was last revised on July 5, 2004.
